<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sean C. Crosby</title>
    <link>https://sccrosby.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sean C. Crosby</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sccrosby.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Making wind forecast corrections with regressions and MLP networks</title>
      <link>https://sccrosby.github.io/post/post006/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sccrosby.github.io/post/post006/</guid>
      <description>The idea Recent skill improvements in meteorological and ocean forecast have been by incorporating observations into model predictions. Numerical model development, by means of improved physical representations, is in many cases suffering from diminishing returns. While ensemble approaches (many) models are useful and provide uncertainty estimates, the assimilation of ever increasing data into models is needed. The folks over at Google&amp;rsquo;s Deep Mind more recently showed that deep neural networks could be used to accurately predict short-term (up to 90-minutes) precipitation events using prior radar observations (Nature article).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can we visualize decision space for different classifiers?</title>
      <link>https://sccrosby.github.io/post/post005/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sccrosby.github.io/post/post005/</guid>
      <description>Support Vector Machines (SVM) are seemingly derived from a intuitive concept, drawing a decision boundary with the widest margin (aka gutter, street, etc.). While this only really applies to the linear problem in which the data are indeed separable, I find it particularly helpful in visualizing the decision space of the model. Unlike a random forest or multi-layer neural network, it is easy to picture model space. While not a novel idea in the slightest, this provoked me to consider decision space for several classification algorithms to hopefully gain insight into other techniques, and with this insight select appropriate methods for future questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dominant wind field patterns from complex empirical orthogonal functions</title>
      <link>https://sccrosby.github.io/post/post002/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sccrosby.github.io/post/post002/</guid>
      <description>Today I was wondering if I can make some sense of a rather large 60-year hindcast of winds in Washington around the Salish Sea. Could I see what the typical wind patterns in the region are? How can I manage this with a rather hefty 1+GB set of spatial wind predictions? This is a good opportunity to explore empirical orthogonal functions (EOFs), also known as principle component analysis (PCA).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean wave transformation with ray-path tracing</title>
      <link>https://sccrosby.github.io/post/post003/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sccrosby.github.io/post/post003/</guid>
      <description>Ray tracing Ray-tracing is a common tool in many fields from Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) to ocean acoustics. In fact ocean acoustics are frequently employed to study whale and porpoise populations as well as detect boats or submarines. The concept is relatively simple, a wave traveling through a medium will bend or refract as its speed in the medium changes. And this is true for ocean waves, the ones you commonly see arriving at the shoreline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://sccrosby.github.io/top/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 10:24:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sccrosby.github.io/top/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a Coastal Oceanographer at the U. S. Geological Survey working with Dr. Eric E. Grossman. Additionally, I am Research Affiliate at Western Washington University mentoring with graduate students in the Geology and Environmental Sciences Departments and occasionally teach Oceanography of the Salish Sea (ESCI491) for the Huxley College of the Environment.
My research interests are inspired by the intersection of land and sea. I study coastal processes including regional wave transformation; high water level modeling (episodic flooding and long-term inundation); sediment transport, beach erosion, and cliff retreat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Research</title>
      <link>https://sccrosby.github.io/top/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 20:28:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sccrosby.github.io/top/research/</guid>
      <description>Modeling Ocean Waves One’s first thought when considering ocean waves might be those that roll gently up our beaches, providing endless entertainment of surfers, body boarders, and beach goers alike. However, waves drive many processes along our coastlines including, beach erosion, coastal flooding, and alongshore transport of sediment, larvae and pollutants. Additionally, large wave energy provide a significant hazard to coastal infrastructure, beach goers and commercial and recreational boating. Therefore accurate, unbiased, high-resolution nearshore wave predictions are needed by both local communities and researchers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
